这是二零二三年普通高等学校招生全国统一考试英语科听力部分。该部分分为第一、第二两节。注意。
that Before I read about your club in the paper today, and I thought I'd phone to
回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。现在是听力试音时间。
find out a bit more.
Yes, certainly. Well, we're a sort of social club for people from different
countries. It's quite a new club.
We have about 50 members at the moment, but we're growing all the time.
That sounds interesting.
I'm British, actually, and I came to Washington about three months ago.
I'm looking for ways to meet people.
What kinds of events do you organize?
Well, we have social get -togethers and sports events, and we also have language
evenings. Could you tell me something about the language evenings?
Yes, every day, except Thursday, we have a language evening.
People can come and practice their languages.
You know, over a drink or something.
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
OK. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form and
some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。听力考试正式开始。请看听力部分第一节。第一节，听下面五段对话。每段对话后有一个小题。从题中所给的
three A, B, and Read
三个选项中选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间。来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话仅读一遍。例如：现在你有五秒钟的时间看试卷上的例题。你将听到以下内容。
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
Yes, it's nine fifteen.
你将有五秒钟的时间。将正确答案标在试卷上。
paper. option five seconds to read the relevant content
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士，所以你选择项，并将其标在试卷上。现在你有。
Could you please tell me how I can get to the student dorm building?
Sure, turn left when you walk out of this register office, past the bookstore, and
you'll see it.
We couldn't ask for a better day, could we Barbara?
I know Steve.
There isn't a cloud in the sky.
I love this time of year.
Me too. The flowers are beautiful, but calling for rain though.
We got any plans this weekend?
We might start with our vegetable garden, then the barbecue.
Sounds fun, but I still want to go fishing with George.
Lisa, I saw Jack this morning.
You mean the former designer of our company?
What's he doing these days?
He said he's got a new job as an art reporter.
Do you often go to the student union Andrew?
Pretty much. Once in a while I meet friends there, and I spend a lot of time
organizing activities in different clubs or associations.
The here. After three A, B, and
第一节到此结束。第二节。听下面五段对话或独白。每段对话或独白后有几个小题。从题中所给的三个选项中，选出最佳选。像听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍。听下面一段对话，回答第六和第七两个小题。现在你有十秒。中的时间阅读这两个小题。
What do think, Terry?
Well, it has one more bedroom than the last flat, and the sitting room is big.
But there is not enough cupboard space in the kitchen.
It's cheaper than the last one we saw, and it is in a good neighborhood.
Well, maybe we'll have to see if the agent has anything else to show us.
What do you think, Terry?
Well, it has one more bedroom than the last flat, and the sitting room is big.
But there is not enough cupboard space in the kitchen.
It's cheaper than the last one we saw, and it is in a good neighborhood.
Well, maybe we'll have to see if the agent has anything else to show us.
听下面一段对话。回答第八和第九两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Thank you, Mrs.
Johnson, for what you've shared with our listeners.
Now, please tell us, do you sometimes feel worried about your daughter now that
she's grown up?
Oh, I worry about her like all parents do.
After she graduated from medical school, she went to volunteer medical service in
Africa. Wow! That's okay if communication was fine, but if there was no internet or
telephone connection, we could sometimes go two weeks without getting in touch with
each other. That often worries me.
Thank you, Mrs.
Johnson, for what you've shared with our listeners.
Now, please tell us, do you sometimes feel worried about your daughter now that
she's grown up?
Oh, I worry about her like all parents do.
After she graduated from medical school, she went to volunteer medical service in
Africa. Wow! That's okay if communication was fine, but if there was no internet or
telephone connection, we could sometimes go two weeks without getting in touch with
each other. That often worries me.
听下面一段对话，回答第十至第。十二三个小题。现在你有十五秒钟的时间阅读这三个小题。
you sometimes worried about service was connection, we could without touch other.
Now, sell yourself in a minute, please.
I graduated from university two years ago and have since been working in an
accounting company.
Apart from the knowledge and skills related to my major, I'm really good with
computers. I have a large amount of experience working with big data.
I think I'm well qualified for the accountant position here.
Why did you choose this company?
Peterson has been my dream company all along.
You value progress and focus on the quality of work more than the quantity.
The flexible working hours and working from home is also attractive.
Uh -huh. What do you think is your biggest weakness?
Well, when I work, I often concentrate so much on what I'm doing that I may have a
hard time dealing with things that come up unexpectedly.
That may be annoying to some people.
All right. Thank you very much.
Now, sell yourself in a minute, please.
I graduated from university two years ago and have since been working in an
accounting company.
Apart from the knowledge and skills related to my major, I'm really good with
computers. I have a large amount of experience working with big data.
I think I'm well qualified for the accountant position here.
Good. Why did you choose this company?
I think I'm accountant position Uh
What do you think is your biggest weakness?
Well, when I work, I often concentrate so much on what I'm doing that I may have a
hard time dealing with things that come That may be annoying to some people.
All right. Thank you very much.
听下面一段对话，回答第十三至第十六四个小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
Thank you much.
So, Robert, I guess you must be well into your third decade as a writer.
How is life treating you?
Fourth decade as a writer?
Hmm. Let me get my calculator out.
Well, I guess I've been writing novels since the 1980s.
So, you're right.
But I have been writing all my life.
And, to answer your question, life has been treating me excellently.
Can I ask you about your childhood?
Were you a bookish child?
In a strange way, I was a non -reader until I turned nine.
I used to play basketball in the schoolyards of Brooklyn.
My father was a high school teacher of physics and chemistry.
And he was a big reader.
He would bring books back from his high school library.
One day, I read the last chapter of a book, the title of which I've long since
forgotten. I liked it so much that I started reading the remainder.
Interestingly, I read the chapters backwards until I got to the beginning.
I really loved the experience.
And I soon became an eager reader.
Then my father would bring piles of books home from the library.
And I would read them all.
And they were all fiction.
I must add that I started reading the books from the start, as opposed to working
backwards. So, Robert, I guess you must be well into your third decade as a writer.
How is life treating you?
Fourth decade as a writer?
Hmm, let me get my calculator out.
Well, I guess I've been writing novels since the 1980s.
So, you're right.
But I have been writing all my life.
And, to answer your question, life has been treating me excellently.
Can I ask you about your childhood?
Were you a bookish child?
In a strange way, I was a non -reader until I turned nine.
I used to play basketball in the schoolyards of Brooklyn.
My father was a high school teacher of physics and chemistry.
And he was a big reader.
He would bring books back from his high school library.
One day, I read the last chapter of a book, the title of which I've long since
forgotten. I liked it so much that I started reading the remainder.
Interestingly, I read the chapters backwards, until I got to the beginning.
I really loved the experience.
And I soon became an eager reader.
Then my father would bring piles of books home from the library.
And I would read them all.
And they were all fiction.
I must add that I started reading the books from the start, as opposed to working
backwards. with you my connection with Open Tchaikovsky Competition.
听下面一段独白。回答第十七至第二十。四个小题。现在你有二十秒钟的时间阅读这四个小题。
It was June 1986, when I came to Moscow to participate in Open Tchaikovsky
Competition at the age of from Chelyabinsk.
This was actually the turning point of my life.
Then, I attended a world music festival in Berlin.
And it was interesting to say that a kid made his breakthrough already at the age of
10. And that was me.
Now, as a judge of the competition,
I can see clearly the huge challenges facing the musicians in the competition.
Where else can you see young players playing within 10 days classical works and
Russian traditional music before coming to the final stage?
As a musician, it's important to give maximum attention and time to your own
reflections of your own feelings.
So, what I'm really looking for in the competition is to meet someone who can touch
me musically. I want to see the seed, at least the seed, of the great tree that can
grow. I would go for this violinist.
I would go for this musician.
Hello, I'm Maxim Vengerov,
I'm very happy to share with my connection with Open Tchaikovsky Competition.
It was June 1986, when I came to Moscow to participate in Open Tchaikovsky
Competition at the age of from Chelyabinsk.
This was actually the turning point of my life.
Then, I attended a world music festival in Berlin.
And it was interesting to say that a kid made his breakthrough already at the age of
And that was me.
Now, as a judge of the competition, I can see clearly the huge challenges facing the
musicians in the competition.
Where else can you see young players playing within 10 days classical works and
Russian traditional music before coming to the final stage?
As a musician, it's important to give maximum attention and time to your own
reflections of your own feelings.
So, what I'm really looking for in the competition is to meet someone who can touch
me musically. I want to see the seed, at least the seed, of the great tree that can
grow. I would go for this violinist.
I would go for this musician.
第二节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的。答案转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. you.
you.
听力部分到此结束。